[
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Angiosperms inhabit relatively diverse environments and may be found ___ higher plants can survive.",
        "answers": [
            "there",
            "wherever",
            "somewhere",
            "then"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "wherever"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Gorillas are quiet animals, __________ they are able to make about twenty different sounds.",
        "answers": [
            "how",
            "in spite of",
            "because of",
            "even though"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "in spite of"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___hardiness, daylilies can be cultivated particularly easily.",
        "answers": [
            "Their",
            "Since their",
            "It is their",
            "Because of their"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "It is their"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Somerset Maugham, a novelist, ________ about  a restless man's quest for inner understanding in The Razor's Edge. ",
        "answers": [
            "who wrote  this",
            "who wrote",
            "when he wrote",
            "wrote"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "wrote"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Sesame ________ a herbaceous plant native to the tropics.  ",
        "answers": [
            " is",
            "which",
            "from",
            "it is"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": " is"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The center of gravity of the human body ___ behind the hip joint.",
        "answers": [
            "locates",
            "locating",
            "to locate",
            "is located"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "is located"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": ". ___millions of galaxies exist in the vast space outside the Milky Way.",
        "answers": [
            "It is estimated that",
            "An estimate that",
            "That is estimated",
            "That the estimated"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "It is estimated that"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "If more than five thousand dollars in  monetary instruments is transported into the United States, a report needs  ________ with the customs office. ",
        "answers": [
            "file",
            "filing",
            "to file ",
            "to be filed"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "to be filed"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "John  F.Kennedy was the youngest president of the United States and ________ to be  assassinated. ",
        "answers": [
            "the fourth",
            "fourth",
            "four",
            "the four"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "the fourth"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "John has  not been able to recall where ________. ",
        "answers": [
            "does she  live",
            "she lives",
            "did she live",
            "lived the  girl"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "she lives"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ in 1635, the Boston Latin School is the oldest public school in the United States.",
        "answers": [
            "Founded",
            "Founding",
            "To found",
            "Having founded"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Founded"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Prescriptions for corrective lenses that are provided by an optometrist are often brought to an optician who ___ the lenses.",
        "answers": [
            "grinding",
            "grinds",
            "they grind",
            "are ground"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "grinds"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Martha Graham, __________, has run her own dance company for half a century.",
        "answers": [
            "is the great modern choreographer",
            "one of the great modern choreographers",
            "that the great modern choreographers",
            "the modern choreographers were great"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "one of the great modern choreographers"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The worldwide race to develop an affordable synthetic fuel has so far consumed billions of dollars and __________ few results.",
        "answers": [
            "yielded",
            "yielding",
            "yield ha",
            "has a yield of"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "yielded"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Fructose is a monosaccharide sugar that is much sweeter ___.",
        "answers": [
            "than cane sugar does",
            "does cane sugar",
            "cane sugar",
            "than cane sugar"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "than cane sugar"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ that as both birds and mammals become larger, their metabolic rates er unit of tissue decrease, and they generally live longer.",
        "answers": [
            "The truth",
            "If true",
            "It is true",
            "To be true"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "It is true"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The history of painting is a fascinating chain of events that probably began with ___",
        "answers": [
            "ever made the very first pictures",
            "the ever made very first pictures",
            "the very first ever made pictures",
            "the very first pictures ever made"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "the very first pictures ever made"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "_____ the arctic regions receive little sunlight, the air there is too cold to hold much moisture.",
        "answers": [
            "Because",
            "The reason that",
            "Therefore",
            "In consequence of"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Because"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Long before children are able to speak or understand a language, __________communicate through facial expressions and by making noises.",
        "answers": [
            "however",
            "they",
            "furthermore",
            "who"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "they"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": ". __________, in the late 1800\u2019s, some libraries had to keep as many as twenty to thirty copies of each of Mary Jane Holmes\u2019s books on hand.",
        "answers": [
            "Inventories showing",
            "That show inventories",
            "Inventories show that",
            "Showing the inventories"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Inventories show that"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The position of the larynx, or voice box, in the neck determines ___, swallows, and vocalizes.",
        "answers": [
            "an animal, how does one breathe",
            "how an animal breathes",
            "an anima breathes, how one",
            "how does an anima breathe"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "how an animal breathes"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Young herons are helpless for a few weeks ___ they learn to fly.",
        "answers": [
            "how",
            "before",
            "despite",
            "since"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "before"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ angles of any triangle always add up to 180 degrees",
        "answers": [
            "If three",
            "The three",
            "Three of",
            "Three are"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "The three"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Alaskan forests ___ five or six miles inland from the Pacific coast.",
        "answers": [
            "penetrate more rarely than",
            "more rarely than penetrate",
            "more penetrate than rarely",
            "rarely penetrate more than"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "rarely penetrate more than"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Cosmetics, rarely noted today for any dangerous properties, have been _____ for serious health problems in the past.",
        "answers": [
            "responsibility",
            "responsible",
            "its responsibility",
            "the responsible"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "responsible"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "In the textile industry, the term \"gunny\" refers to ___burlap that is not of the best quality.",
        "answers": [
            "not expensive a",
            "expensive, not",
            "not an expensive",
            "an inexpensive"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "an inexpensive"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The skyscraper, ___,is an architectural form that originated in the United States.",
        "answers": [
            "is a tall commercial structure",
            "a tall commercial structure",
            "a tall commercial structure which",
            "of which a tall commercial structure"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "a tall commercial structure"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ as 2500 B.C., the Egyptians used mirrors made of highly polished metal.",
        "answers": [
            "In early",
            "As early",
            "Early",
            "Was as early"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "As early"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "So little ________ that he  failed the examination. ",
        "answers": [
            "did the student know",
            "the student knew",
            "the student had  known",
            "knew the student"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "did the student know"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "George did not do well in the class because ________.  ",
        "answers": [
            "he studied  bad",
            "he was not good studywise",
            "he was a badly  student",
            "he failed to study properly"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "he failed to study properly"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The leaves and stems of the alfalfa plant are the only parts of the plant ___.",
        "answers": [
            "the uses for livestock fees",
            "for using livestock feed",
            "used for livestock feed",
            "they are used for livestock feed"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "they are used for livestock feed"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "A fuel is a substance used ___ light, heat, or energy.",
        "answers": [
            "generating",
            "generates",
            "to generate",
            "it is generating"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "to generate"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Closed plane figures like the square or the equilateral triangle can be grouped into a class __________polygons.",
        "answers": [
            "called",
            "to call",
            "is called",
            "call as"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "called"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The extent of the harmful effect of locoweeds on animals depends on the soil ___the plants grow.",
        "answers": [
            "which",
            "which in",
            "in which",
            "in"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "in which"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ reaches the cells of the body, it is oxidized, or slowly burned",
        "answers": [
            "As digested food",
            "Digested food that",
            "Food is digested",
            "Why does digested food"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "As digested food"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ became a state in 1876",
        "answers": [
            "When Colorado",
            "Colorado",
            "It was Colorado",
            "Colorado, which"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Colorado"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "As Mercury moves in its solar orbit, _____ its axis, an imaginary line that runs through its center.",
        "answers": [
            "rotates it on",
            "it rotates on",
            "on rotates it",
            "rotates on it"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "it rotates on"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The railways system is very efficient as the trains always arrive ___ time.",
        "answers": [
            "up",
            "at",
            "for",
            "on"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "for"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "You can tell just looking at their out of date equipment that the company is well ___ the times.",
        "answers": [
            "behind",
            "across",
            "under",
            "outside"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "outside"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ that of iron construction, the technology for constructing buildings with developed rather rapidly. reinforced concrete",
        "answers": [
            "Dissimilar",
            "Different",
            "Not likely",
            "Unlike"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Unlike"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "In his writing, John Crowe Ransom describes what ___the spiritual barrenness of society brought about by science and technology.",
        "answers": [
            "he considers",
            "does he consider",
            "considers",
            "considers it"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "he considers"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ duties are placed on commodities according to their value.",
        "answers": [
            "Ordinarily, tariff",
            "Ordinary tariffs are",
            "On ordinary tariff",
            "Tariffs are ordinarily"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Ordinarily, tariff"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Not only can walking fish live out of water, _____ they can also travel short distances over land.",
        "answers": [
            "neither",
            "and",
            "but",
            "if"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "but"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "_____ Eijah McCoy\u2019s invention of the lubricating cup in the early 1870\u2019s, machinery had to be stopped in order to be lubricated.",
        "answers": [
            "Before",
            "When",
            "While",
            "Lately"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Before"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "_____ mineral content in the bones of very young children is low compared to that of adults.",
        "answers": [
            "If the",
            "That is",
            "The",
            "It is the"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "The"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "With affection and humor, poet Phyllis McGinley ___of ordinary life.",
        "answers": [
            "the virtues were praised",
            "praised the virtues",
            "she praised the virtues",
            "her praise of the virtues"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "praised the virtues"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "In addition to pleasure, _____ excitement, challenge, and relaxation",
        "answers": [
            "the providing of games",
            "games if providing",
            "the games which provide",
            "games provide"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "games provide"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The Hawthrone studies, _____ the monotonous working conditions of factory personnel, were a major contribution to industrial psychology",
        "answers": [
            "in which the investigation of",
            "were they investigated",
            "which were investigation",
            "an investigation of"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "an investigation of"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Vaporization in connection with general ___ has a marked effect on long \u2013 term climate.",
        "answers": [
            "atmospheric conditions that",
            "conditions are atmospheric",
            "are atmospheric conditions",
            "atmospheric conditions"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "conditions are atmospheric"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "________ is entirely up to him. ",
        "answers": [
            "How he  travels",
            "How traveling",
            "He travels",
            "How is he  traveling"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "How he  travels"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Even though John F. Kennedy failed to receive the Democratic Party\u2019s vice presidential nomination in 1956, _____ won their nomination for President in 1960.",
        "answers": [
            "he",
            "who",
            "and",
            "but"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "he"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The University of Georgia, __________ in 1785, was the first state supported university in the United States.",
        "answers": [
            "chartered",
            "was chartered",
            "it was chartered",
            "to be chartered"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "chartered"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Because the saxophone is an excellent solo instrument, ___ in some important orchestral works.",
        "answers": [
            "it is featured",
            "while featured",
            "if featured",
            "feature it"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "it is featured"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The position of the larynx, or voice box, in the neck determines ___, swallows, and vocalizes.",
        "answers": [
            "an animal, how does one breathe",
            "how an animal breathes",
            "an anima breathes, how one",
            "how does an anima breathe"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "how an animal breathes"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "When linguists encounter a new  language, ________ work to identify all of the sounds it contains. ",
        "answers": [
            " who",
            "they",
            "and",
            "those"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "they"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Some procedures used for laboratory analysis of archaeological specimens are ___ procedures conducted in crime laboratories",
        "answers": [
            "resemble",
            "similar to",
            "same as",
            "alike"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "similar to"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The windmill, which has been used for hundreds of years to pump water and grind grains, ___ redesigned to produce electricity",
        "answers": [
            "it is now being",
            "it now can",
            "is now being",
            "now being"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "is now being"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The slide rule uses sliding scales with marks ___ numbers and their logarithms.",
        "answers": [
            "representing",
            ") represented",
            "are represented",
            "they are representing"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "representing"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ matter in one form is transmuted to another form, a phase change is said to have taken place.",
        "answers": [
            "Such",
            "Then",
            "Whenever",
            "Seldom"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Whenever"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "_____ limit to the extent which human beings may benefit from their own inventive genius",
        "answers": [
            "Not any",
            "Has no",
            "There is no",
            "It not"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "There is no"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The knee is the joint __________the thigh bone meets the large bone of the lower leg.",
        "answers": [
            "when",
            "where",
            "why",
            "which"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "where"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "__________the history of the tough, strong-willed Nebraska farmer.",
        "answers": [
            "Not only is much of the history of Nebraska",
            "Although it is much of the history of Nebraska that is",
            "It is much the history of Nebraska's being",
            "Much of the history of Nebraska is"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Much of the history of Nebraska is"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "All of the people at the AAME conference are ________.  ",
        "answers": [
            "mathematic  teachers",
            "mathematics teachers",
            "mathematics teacher",
            "mathematic's  teachers"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "mathematics teachers"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": " ________ \"cultural diffusion\" refers to the spread of customs or practices from  one culture to another. ",
        "answers": [
            "To phrase",
            "Phrased",
            "To the  phrase",
            "The phrase"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "The phrase"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The Order of Elks  has been in existence ________ 1868. ",
        "answers": [
            "starting in",
            " since",
            "after",
            "founded"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": " since"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ in 1635, the Boston Latin School is the oldest public school in the United States.",
        "answers": [
            "Founded",
            "Founding",
            "To found",
            "Having founded"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Founded"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "At an experimental agricultural station, many types of  grass are grown ________ various conditions. ",
        "answers": [
            "under",
            " underneath",
            "below",
            "beneath"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "under"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "________ did Arthur realize that there was  danger. ",
        "answers": [
            "Upon entering the store",
            "When he entered the  store",
            "After he had entered the store",
            "Only after entering the  store"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Only after entering the  store"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "As soon as ________ with an acid, salt, and sometimes water,  is formed. ",
        "answers": [
            "a base will react",
            "a base reacts",
            "a base is  reacting",
            "the reaction of a base"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "a base reacts"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Helen Keller lost both  her sight and hearing after a severe illness ________. ",
        "answers": [
            "of her age in 19  months",
            "she was 19 months old",
            "when she was 19 months  old",
            "when 19 months old she was"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "when she was 19 months  old"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ were stones piled at intervals",
        "answers": [
            "The earliest road markers",
            "The earliest road markers, which",
            "Road markers were the earliest",
            "Until the earliest road markers"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "The earliest road markers"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "_____ of staging a play that help the audience understand its structure and meaning",
        "answers": [
            "Specific aspects",
            "When specific aspects",
            "Specific aspects are",
            "There are specific aspects"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "There are specific aspects"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The seating of musicians in an orchestra is arranged __________to produce the desired blend of sounds from the various musical sections",
        "answers": [
            "the conductor of",
            "from the conductor",
            "the conductor and",
            "by the conductor"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "by the conductor"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The teacher suggested  that her students ________ experiences with ESP. ",
        "answers": [
            "write a composition on  their",
            "to write composition about the",
            "wrote some compositions of his  or her",
            "had written any compositions for his"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "write a composition on  their"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": " ________, the jaguar used to roam freely in the southwestern United States.  ",
        "answers": [
            "It is now found  only in Central and South America",
            "Now finding in Central and South  America",
            "To be found in Central and South America",
            "Now found only  in Central and South America"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Now found only  in Central and South America"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ executive and administrative authority in the United States government rests with a President who is elected for a four-year term.",
        "answers": [
            "That the",
            "The",
            "It is the",
            "There is the"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "The"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ tributaries of the Mississippi River system were navigated by steamboats during the period before the outbreak of the Civil War",
        "answers": [
            "More than forty",
            "More than forty were",
            "Forty more than",
            "There were more than forty"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "More than forty"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Before 8000 B. C. wheat did not grow as prolifically ___ it does today.",
        "answers": [
            "like",
            "as",
            "for",
            "than"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "as"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "__________ one time, Manchester, New Hampshire, was the home of the most productive cotton mills in the world.",
        "answers": [
            "On",
            "At",
            "By",
            "To"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "At"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "My opinion is that they don't know what to do and are merely playing ___ time.",
        "answers": [
            "to",
            "for",
            "at",
            "in"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "for"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ stereophonic phonograph records, two recordings are made of the same musical performance",
        "answers": [
            "Creates",
            "Created",
            "The creating of",
            "To create"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "To create"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The colors of a rainbow ___ arranged in the same order.",
        "answers": [
            "which are always",
            "and they are always",
            "always",
            "are always"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "are always"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Billie Holiday's reputation as a great jazz-blues singer rests on her ability __________emotional depth to her songs.",
        "answers": [
            "be giving",
            "are given",
            "being given",
            "to give"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "to give"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Since the earth's crust is much thicker under  the continents, equipment would have to be capable of drilling through 100,000  feet of rock to investigate the mantle ________ . ",
        "answers": [
            "beneath them",
            "beneath  their",
            "beneath its",
            "beneath they"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "beneath them"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "If one is suffering from a psychosomatic  illness, that is, a disease contributed to by mental anxiety, one may still feel  very ________ . ",
        "answers": [
            "badly",
            "bad",
            "worsely",
            "worser"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "bad"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___, some of the Earth\u2019s interior heat escapes to the surface.",
        "answers": [
            "A volcano erupts",
            "A volcano whether erupts",
            "A volcano erupts it",
            "If a volcano erupts"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "If a volcano erupts"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "In 1914 a bronze tablet _____ Harriet Tubman was placed at the entrance of the Cayuga Country Courthouse in Aubum, New York.",
        "answers": [
            "honored",
            "for honor",
            "in honor of",
            "was honoring"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "in honor of"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Upon hatching, ________. ",
        "answers": [
            "young ducks know how to  swim",
            "swimming is known by young ducks",
            "the knowledge of swimming is  in young ducks",
            "how to swim is known in young ducks"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "young ducks know how to  swim"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Perhaps the oldest theories of business cycles are  ________ that linked their cause to fluctuations of the harvest. ",
        "answers": [
            " whatever",
            "everything",
            "those",
            "them"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "those"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": " Trace minerals are ________ are elements needed in greater quantities. ",
        "answers": [
            "as important to  healthy human tissue as",
            "most important to healthy human  tissue",
            "to healthy human tissue as important",
            "important to healthy human  tissue"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "as important to  healthy human tissue as"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "In central Georgia, archaeological evidence indicates that Native Americans first inhabited the area ___.",
        "answers": [
            "since thirteen centuries",
            "thirteen centuries ago",
            "the previous thirteen centuries",
            "thirteen centuries were before"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "thirteen centuries ago"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The difference between libel and slander is that libel is printed while__________.",
        "answers": [
            "spoken is slander",
            "Living",
            "They will live",
            "If they lived"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "They will live"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "When ___in arctic regions, the Aleuts construct igloos as temporary winter shelters.",
        "answers": [
            "travel",
            "to travel",
            "traveling them",
            "traveling"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "travel"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Resin is a substance that ___in water.",
        "answers": [
            "does not dissolve",
            "do not dissolve",
            "not dissolving",
            "not dissolved"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "not dissolving"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The people of Western Canada  have been considering ________ themselves from the rest of the provinces. ",
        "answers": [
            "to separate",
            " separated",
            "separate",
            "separating"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "separating"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The spiral threads of a spider?s web have a sticky substance on them ___ insects.",
        "answers": [
            "traps",
            "trap its",
            "which traps",
            "which it traps"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "which traps"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The gibbon ranges over ___ other apes do.",
        "answers": [
            "than an area wider",
            "wider than the area",
            "a wider area than",
            "an area wider than are"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "a wider area than"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "There is evidence that prehistoric humans used fire ___ 400,000 B. C.",
        "answers": [
            "so early",
            "the earliest",
            "as early as",
            "so early that"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "as early as"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "You can tell she has hit the ___ time because of the huge car she drives.",
        "answers": [
            "high",
            "massive",
            "large",
            "big"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "massive"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Oscillatona, one of  the few plants that can move about, ________ a wavy, gliding motion. ",
        "answers": [
            " having",
            "has",
            "being",
            "with"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "has"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ reaches the cells of the body, it is oxidized, or slowly burned",
        "answers": [
            "As digested food",
            "Digested food that",
            "Food is digested",
            "Why does digested food"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "As digested food"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Asteroids are small and therefore very difficult to identify, even when ___ to Earth",
        "answers": [
            "quite closely",
            "are being quite close",
            "are they quite closely",
            "they are quite close"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "they are quite close"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "A floodplain is an extension of a river channel, _____ not inundated except during a flood.",
        "answers": [
            "where is it",
            "but it is",
            "or is",
            "in case it"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "but it is"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ a lonely and rugged life, far from home and family.",
        "answers": [
            "Wherever the early prospector lived",
            "The early prospector lived",
            "Not only did the early prospector live",
            "The early prospector living"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "The early prospector lived"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The truck ________ crashed into the back of a bus  scattering glass everywhere. ",
        "answers": [
            "loading with empty bottles",
            "which loading with empty  bottles",
            "it was loading with empty bottles",
            "loaded with empty  bottles"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "loaded with empty  bottles"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ principal types of acceleration: linear and angular.",
        "answers": [
            "There are tow",
            "Two of them",
            "The two",
            "Two"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "There are tow"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Under the guidance of choreographers, Martha Graham and Jerome Robbins, American dance ___new levels of artistic achievement.",
        "answers": [
            "reaching",
            "has reached",
            "reach",
            "have reached"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "has reached"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Sarah Frances Whiting opened the ___ of physics in the United States in 1878.",
        "answers": [
            "undergraduate teaching was in a second laboratory",
            "second teaching laboratory of undergraduate",
            "undergraduate teaching laboratory was second",
            "second undergraduate teaching laboratory"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "second undergraduate teaching laboratory"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "A biologist does not merely describe organisms, but tries to learn ___act as they do.",
        "answers": [
            "what cause them to",
            "causes them to what",
            "what to cause them",
            "what does to them"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "causes them to what"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": " Chemists are not sure ________ . ",
        "answers": [
            "how precisely can cold fusion  occur",
            "cold fusion can occur precisely how",
            "precisely how cold fusion  can occur",
            "can cold fusion occur precisely how"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "precisely how cold fusion  can occur"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "In 1938, when Benny Goodman\u2019s orchestra presented a concert at the prestigious Carnegie Hall, ___ was clear that jazz had at last been fully accepted",
        "answers": [
            "There",
            "Which",
            "And",
            "It"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "It"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Writing pens are made in ___of shapes, sizes, and colors.",
        "answers": [
            "endless variety an almost",
            "variety an almost endless",
            "an almost endless variety",
            "almost variety an endless"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "an almost endless variety"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Mary Eliza McDowell\u2019s introduction to social service came ___, when she assisted victims of the great Chicago Fire of 1871",
        "answers": [
            "was sixteen years old",
            "had sixteen years",
            "at age sixteen",
            "sixteen"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "at age sixteen"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The glaciers that reached the Pacific Coast were valley glaciers, and between those tongues of ice ___ that allowed the original forests to survive.",
        "answers": [
            "that many sanctuaries were",
            "were many sanctuaries",
            "were there many sanctuaries",
            "there the many sanctuaries"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "were many sanctuaries"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Groups of muscles in the head direct the actions necessary for _____.",
        "answers": [
            "chew and swallow",
            "to chew and to swallow",
            "being chewed and swallowing",
            "chewing and swallowing"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "chewing and swallowing"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The ancient Hopewell people of North America probably cultivated corn and ___crops, but hunting and gathering were still of critical importance in their economy.",
        "answers": [
            "another",
            "the other\u2019s",
            "other",
            "other than"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "other"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The fragrances of many natural substances come from oils, ___ these oils may be used in manufacturing perfumes.",
        "answers": [
            "of",
            "from",
            "whether",
            "and"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "and"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "________ air traffic controllers guide planes through  conditions of near zero visibility. ",
        "answers": [
            "They talk with  pilots and watch their approach on radar,",
            "Talking with pilots and  watching their approach on radar,",
            "Talk with pilots and watch their  approach on radar,",
            "When they talked with pilots and watched their  approach on radar,"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Talking with pilots and  watching their approach on radar,"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Aspirin  is used ________ a constriction of the blood vessels. ",
        "answers": [
            "the  counteraction",
            "to counteract",
            "counteract",
            " counteracting"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "to counteract"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The theory of Continental Drift assumes that there  ________ long-term climatic changes in many areas during the past. ",
        "answers": [
            "must have  been",
            "must be",
            "must have",
            "must"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "must have  been"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "In 1852 _____ one hundred piano-makers in New York alone.",
        "answers": [
            "were",
            "had been",
            "there were",
            "being that there"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "there were"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The mechanism by which brain cells store memories is ___clearly understood.",
        "answers": [
            "none",
            "no",
            "not",
            "nor"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "none"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ raw materials into useful products is called manufacturing.",
        "answers": [
            "Transform",
            "Transforming",
            "Being transformed",
            "When transforming"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Transform"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "With new technology, cameras can take  pictures of underwater valleys ________ color. ",
        "answers": [
            "within",
            " for",
            "in",
            "by"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "in"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Although one of his ships  succeeded in sailing all the way back to Spain through the Cape of Good Hope,  Magellan never completed the first circumnavigation of the world, and ________.  ",
        "answers": [
            "and most of his  crew didn't too",
            "neither most of his crew did",
            "neither did  most of his crew",
            "and most of his crew didn't also"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "neither did  most of his crew"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Both nickel and iron are whitish metals ___.",
        "answers": [
            "that are attracted by magnets",
            "that magnets are attracted by them",
            "are attracted by magnets",
            "magnets that attract them"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "that are attracted by magnets"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ red clover, high in protein content, is an extremely important leguminous hay and pasture plant of the eastern United States.",
        "answers": [
            "The",
            "There us the",
            "It is the",
            "That the"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "The"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Since Tampa has a mild winter climate, _____ as a tourist resort.",
        "answers": [
            "popular it",
            "that as popular",
            "popular",
            "it is popular"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "it is popular"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Helium is ___ all gases to liquefy and is impossible to solidify at normal air pressure.",
        "answers": [
            "more than difficult",
            "the most difficult of",
            "more difficult of",
            "most difficult"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "the most difficult of"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Overexposure to the sun causes ________ health  problems. ",
        "answers": [
            "various",
            "among",
            "but",
            "of"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "various"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Duke Ellington was a composer, conductor, and pianist ___ ranked as one of the greatest of all jazz figures",
        "answers": [
            "him",
            "although",
            "or",
            "who"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "who"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Mammals have a larger, more well-developed brain _____ other animals",
        "answers": [
            "than do",
            "that are having",
            "which have",
            "that do"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "than do"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Mary Cassatt specialized __________ mothers with their children.",
        "answers": [
            "painted",
            "who painted",
            "paintings",
            "in painting"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "in painting"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Every year Canadian ___ about 75 percent of their exports to the United States.",
        "answers": [
            "businesses that sell",
            "selling businesses",
            "businesses sell",
            "that sell to businesses"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "businesses sell"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Of  Charles Dickens' many novels, \"Great Expectations\" is perhaps ________ to many  readers. ",
        "answers": [
            "the most satisfying one",
            "most satisfying one",
            "more than  satisfying one",
            "the more satisfying than"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "the most satisfying one"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Green ___have the power to make food from substances found in the air and soil.",
        "answers": [
            "only plants",
            "plants alone",
            "the only plants",
            "plants are alone"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "plants alone"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ executive and administrative authority in the United States government rests with a President who is elected for a four-year term.",
        "answers": [
            "That the",
            "The",
            "It is the",
            "There is the"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "The"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ social crusade aroused Elizabeth Williams\u2019enthusiasm more than the expansion of educational facilities for immigrants to the United States.",
        "answers": [
            "No",
            "Nothing",
            "Not",
            "None"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "No"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Modern  blimps like the famous Goodyear blimps ________ the first ones in that they are  filled with helium instead of hydrogen. ",
        "answers": [
            "differ  from",
            "different from",
            "is different from",
            " different"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "differ  from"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Although the Ojibwa Indians fought frequently with the  Sioux, they didn't have ________ with early white settlers. ",
        "answers": [
            "much  contact",
            "lots contact",
            "many contact",
            "large contact"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "much  contact"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Their keen senses of hearing and smell have made some types of dogs _____ in hunting and tracking and as security guards",
        "answers": [
            "as valuable",
            "of the value",
            "are valued",
            "valuable"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "valuable"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Astronomy developed from the observation _____ through regular cycles of motion.",
        "answers": [
            "going to heavenly bodies",
            "the heavenly bodies going",
            "heavenly bodies that go",
            "that the heavenly bodies go"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "that the heavenly bodies go"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Astronomer Maria Mitchell was the first woman _____ to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences.",
        "answers": [
            "to be elected",
            "was elected",
            "which she was elected",
            "for her to be elected"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "to be elected"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Ground plans and contour maps of the Earth ___from aerial photographs.",
        "answers": [
            "can be drawn",
            "can draw",
            "to draw",
            "drawn"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "can be drawn"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The greater the demand,  ________ the price. ",
        "answers": [
            "higher",
            "high",
            "the higher",
            "the high"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "the higher"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "In the textile industry, the term \u201cgunny\u201d refers to ___burlap that is not of the best quality.",
        "answers": [
            "not expensive a",
            "expensive, not",
            "not an expensive",
            "an inexpensive"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "an inexpensive"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": ". ___ their senses, many-celled animals perceive what is happening in their environment.",
        "answers": [
            "Means of",
            "By means of",
            "Of the means by",
            "By means"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "By means of"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Loganberries can be used in jams ___ their juice.",
        "answers": [
            "and for",
            "while",
            "too",
            "in which"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "and for"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The ________wanted to  continue their tour even though the bus had broken down. ",
        "answers": [
            "tourist",
            "tourists  have",
            "tourists",
            "tourist had"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "tourists"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": " A symbol of the ancient competition, the Olympic flame burns ________ throughout  the games. ",
        "answers": [
            "in a continuous way",
            "continuous",
            " continuously",
            "continual"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": " continuously"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ all data into electronic pulses.",
        "answers": [
            "The computer input unit changes",
            "Changing input, the computer unit",
            "Which changes the computer input unit",
            "Changes in the computer input units"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "The computer input unit changes"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Acids are chemical compounds that, in water solution, have __________, a corrosive action on metals, and the ability to turn certain blue vegetable dyes red.",
        "answers": [
            "tastes sharp",
            "sharp-tasting",
            "a sharp taste",
            "tasting sharp"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "a sharp taste"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Alexander Graham Bell once told his family that he would rather be remembered as a teacher of the deaf ___of the telephone.",
        "answers": [
            "than inventing",
            "than as the inventor",
            "the invention",
            "as the inventor"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "than as the inventor"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The professor's  daughter taught ________ to play the guitar. ",
        "answers": [
            "himself",
            " hers",
            "herself",
            "his"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "herself"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The adder is a venomous snake  ________ bite may prove fatal to humans. ",
        "answers": [
            " its",
            "whom its",
            "that",
            "whose"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "whose"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ a continuous mass of water on the Earth?s surface, all continents are islands in the strictest sense of the word.",
        "answers": [
            "The form of the oceans",
            "Since the oceans form",
            "To form the oceans",
            "That the oceans form"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Since the oceans form"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Fruit is one of the most abundant, nutritious, and ___ foods a person can eat.",
        "answers": [
            "delicious",
            "too delicious",
            "is it delicious",
            "tastes delicious"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "delicious"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "________ of the  Stamp Act in 1865 provoked strong opposition among the American colonists.  ",
        "answers": [
            "The passage  was",
            "It was the passage",
            "Before the passage",
            "The  passage"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "The  passage"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Goddard developed the first rocket to fly faster  ________. ",
        "answers": [
            "than sound is",
            "does sound",
            "sound",
            "than  sound"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "than  sound"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Nitric  acid ________ copper to give off brown fumes of nitrogen dioxide. ",
        "answers": [
            "on reacting  with",
            "reacting to",
            "reacts with",
            "is reacting  with"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "reacts with"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "A number of modern sculptors have rejected ___ of minimal and environmental art and developed a style of extreme realism.",
        "answers": [
            "which abstract qualities",
            "there are abstract qualities",
            "the abstract qualities",
            "the qualities are abstract"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "the abstract qualities"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ choose to live in or near metropolitan areas simply because they like the rapid pace of city life.",
        "answers": [
            "So large numbers of people to",
            "There are large numbers of people",
            "Large numbers of people",
            "Large numbers of people who"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Large numbers of people"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Sandra Day O\u2019Connor, the first woman member of the United States Supreme Court, believed that the courts should interpret the laws ___ legislate",
        "answers": [
            "than attempt to rather",
            "rather than attempt to",
            "to attempt rather than",
            "attempt rather than to"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "rather than attempt to"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "People's expectations for a higher standard of living increase __________.",
        "answers": [
            "conditions in their community improve",
            "since conditions in their improving community",
            "conditions improve in their community",
            "as conditions in their community improve"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "as conditions in their community improve"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "If you really want to send that letter off today, it's ___ time you went to the post office.",
        "answers": [
            "high",
            "quick",
            "proper",
            "right"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "proper"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Like other women ___in the field of medicine, Sara Mayo found the beginning years difficult.",
        "answers": [
            "who they pioneered",
            "they pioneered",
            "who pioneered",
            "pioneered"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "who pioneered"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Children with parents whose guidance is firm, consistent, and rational are inclined ___high levels of self-confidence.",
        "answers": [
            "possess",
            "have possessed",
            "to possess",
            "possessing"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "to possess"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "In 1961 the entertainer Chubby Checker introduced a __________ to New York\u2019s rock\u2019n \u2018 roll fans.",
        "answers": [
            "new dance, the twist",
            "twist, was the new dance",
            "twist, the new dance that",
            "new dance is the twist"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "new dance, the twist"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "________ the bones of prehistoric man, scientists hope to  determine what their owners ate. ",
        "answers": [
            "By studying",
            "In study of",
            "To study",
            " Studying"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "By studying"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "There are  two basic kinds of air compressors, reciprocating and ________ ",
        "answers": [
            "another kind  that is rotating",
            "one that rotates",
            "a rotating  kind",
            "rotating"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "rotating"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___, The Yearling, won a Pulitzer Prize.",
        "answers": [
            "Marjorie Rawlings\u2019 best work was",
            "Marjorie Rawlings\u2019 best work",
            "Her best work was Marjorie Rawlings\u2019",
            "That Marjorie Rawlings\u2019 best work"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Marjorie Rawlings\u2019 best work"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The business has lost a lot of orders recently and is going through a ___ time.",
        "answers": [
            "slender",
            "poor",
            "thin",
            "acute"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "poor"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "If you want to grow as a business and attract new customers you must ___ with the times.",
        "answers": [
            "move",
            "follow",
            "keep",
            "hold"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "follow"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "It is now believed that some damage to tissues may result  ________ them to frequent X-rays. ",
        "answers": [
            "the exposing",
            "from  exposure",
            "from exposing",
            "expose"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "from exposing"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Many  plants can grow in water, without any soil, ________ nutrients are added. ",
        "answers": [
            "as long as",
            "sure  that",
            "above all",
            "of necessity"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "as long as"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The fragrances of many natural substances come from oils, ___ these oils may be used in manufacturing perfumes.",
        "answers": [
            "of",
            "from",
            "whether",
            "and"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "and"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "It is unlikely that a nation would choose war if its goals _____ peacefully",
        "answers": [
            "meet",
            "could be met",
            "having been met",
            "would have met"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "could be met"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Many English _____ were opposed to the American Revolution of 1776 moved to Canada, where they were known as United Empire Loyalists.",
        "answers": [
            "settling there",
            "they settled",
            "who were settlers",
            "settlers who"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "settlers who"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "From 1946 to 1949, __________ William Henry Hastie served as governor of the Virgin Islands.",
        "answers": [
            "the lawyer",
            "he was the lawyer",
            "the lawyer who",
            "was the lawyer"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "the lawyer"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "In sculpture __________\u201dmodeling\u201d denotes a way of shaping clay, wax, or other pliable materials.",
        "answers": [
            "to the term",
            "is termed",
            "the term",
            "to term"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "the term"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The state of Maine generally has cooler temperatures than ___",
        "answers": [
            "there are most other states",
            "most other state which have",
            "most other states have",
            "having most other states"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "most other states have"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Few natural elements exist in ________  that they are rarely seen in their natural environments. ",
        "answers": [
            "such small  quantities",
            "so small quantities",
            "very small quantities",
            "small  quantity"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "such small  quantities"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Culture influences the way ________. ",
        "answers": [
            "viewing the  world",
            "that we view the world",
            "the world view",
            "is the view of  the world"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "that we view the world"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Out of John Kenneth Galbraith's The Affluent Society  ________ for an increase in public goods, potentially at the expense of private  goods. ",
        "answers": [
            "came the argument",
            "his argument",
            "argued",
            "the economist  is arguing"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "came the argument"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "We all saw the athlete when he  ________ the fastest mile ever run at the school. ",
        "answers": [
            "run",
            " running",
            "ran",
            "had run"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "ran"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Some procedures used for laboratory analysis of archaeological specimens are ___ procedures conducted in crime laboratories",
        "answers": [
            "resemble",
            "similar to",
            "same as",
            "alike"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "similar to"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The windmill, which has been used for hundreds of years to pump water and grind grains, ___ redesigned to produce electricity",
        "answers": [
            "it is now being",
            "it now can",
            "is now being",
            "now being"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "is now being"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Lunar eclipses occur each time the Earth blocks the Sun\u2019s light from the Moon ___ the Moon\u2019s full phase.",
        "answers": [
            "during",
            "whether",
            "in which",
            "whenever"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "during"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "_____ commonly chosen as the first step to a career in public office.",
        "answers": [
            "Why legal training is",
            "Legal training is",
            "Legal training that is",
            "It is legal training"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Legal training is"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Quasars __________ emitting extremely intense radio waves and visible radiation.",
        "answers": [
            "Star-like objects are",
            "Star-like, they are objects",
            "are star-like objects",
            "are they star-like objects"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "are star-like objects"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The large compound eyes of the dragonfly ___ to see moving objects almost eighteen feet away.",
        "answers": [
            "to enable it",
            "enabling it",
            "it enables",
            "enable it"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "enable it"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Adhesive, such as glue, tape, and gum, vary with the purpose ___ intended.",
        "answers": [
            "they were for",
            "for they were",
            "which were they",
            "for which they were"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "for which they were"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "In the Osage tribe of Oklahoma, beaded belts _____ who held a high social status.",
        "answers": [
            "only by women were fashioned",
            "by women were fashioned only",
            "were fashioned only by women",
            "were by women fashioned only"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "were fashioned only by women"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The wood of the holly tree, close-grained and very hard, _____ for musical instruments, furniture, and interior design.",
        "answers": [
            "is used",
            "uses",
            "used",
            "is using"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "is used"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Because its leaves remain green long after being picked, rosemary ___ associated with the idea of remembrance.",
        "answers": [
            "and becomes",
            "became",
            "becoming",
            "to become"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "and becomes"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ of minerals, which are chemical elements or compounds of varying purity",
        "answers": [
            "The consistency of rocks",
            "Rocks, consisting",
            "Rocks consist",
            "Whereas rocks consist"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Rocks consist"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The topology of Mars is more ___ than that of any other planet.",
        "answers": [
            "like that of the Earth",
            "the Earth\u2019s like that of",
            "like the Earth of that",
            "that of the Earth\u2019s like"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "like that of the Earth"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The edible tube mushroom __________ a cushion-like, moist cap that is light brown or darkish red.",
        "answers": [
            "which has",
            "to have",
            "having",
            "has"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "has"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": " ________, which is the highest in the range, appears challenging. ",
        "answers": [
            "Climbing the  mountain",
            "The mountains",
            "Up the mountain",
            "The mountain that  is"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Climbing the  mountain"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Legumes take  nitrogen into their roots ________ the air. ",
        "answers": [
            "except",
            " however",
            "but",
            "from"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "from"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The spiral threads of a spider\u2019s web have a sticky substance on them ___ insects.",
        "answers": [
            "traps",
            "trap its",
            "which traps",
            "which it traps"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "which traps"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Because the saxophone is an excellent solo instrument, ___ in some important orchestral works.",
        "answers": [
            "it is featured",
            "while featured",
            "if featured",
            "feature it"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "it is featured"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Thanks to modern irrigation, crops now grow abundantly in areas where once __________ cacti and sagebrush could live.",
        "answers": [
            "nor",
            "not the",
            "none other",
            "nothing but"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "nothing but"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "________ techniques have  been developed in recent years to diagnose (genetic diseases in the developing  fetus. ",
        "answers": [
            "Several",
            "There are several",
            "They are  several",
            "Several of"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Several"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Nestled along the shoreline of Hudson Bay ________. ",
        "answers": [
            "are several  recently settled Inuit communities",
            "several recently settled Inuit  communities are there",
            "near several recently settled Inuit  communities",
            "is where several recently settled Inuit  communities"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "are several  recently settled Inuit communities"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "In 1938, when Benny Goodman?s orchestra presented a concert at the prestigious Carnegie Hall, ___ was clear that jazz had at last been fully accepted",
        "answers": [
            "There",
            "Which",
            "And",
            "It"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "It"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Duke Ellington was a composer, conductor, and pianist ___ ranked as one of the greatest of all jazz figures",
        "answers": [
            "him",
            "although",
            "or",
            "who"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "who"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": " Some of the rainwater from clouds evaporates before ________. ",
        "answers": [
            "reaching the  ground",
            "to reach the ground",
            "reach the ground",
            "the ground  reaches"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "reaching the  ground"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "_______ are prepared from flour  or meal derived from some form of grain. ",
        "answers": [
            "With bakery  products",
            "While bakery products",
            "Bakery products",
            "They are bakery  products"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Bakery products"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Rhododendrons would  rather ________ in shady places, and so would azaleas. ",
        "answers": [
            "to  grow",
            "growing",
            "grown",
            "grow"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "grow"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Snow aids farmers by keeping heat in the lower ground levels, thereby _____ from freezing.",
        "answers": [
            "to save the seeds",
            "saving the seeds",
            "which saves the seeds",
            "the seeds saved"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "saving the seeds"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The United States Congress made Washington, D.C., _____ in 1800.",
        "answers": [
            "after the government center",
            "of the government center",
            "the center of government",
            "then the center of government"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "the center of government"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Before Geraldine Ferraro was selected as the Democratic Party\u2019s vice presidential candidate in 1984, no woman ___ run for national office in the United States on a major party ticket.",
        "answers": [
            "ever has",
            "never had",
            "had ever",
            "having never"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "had ever"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "With x \u2013 ray microscopes scientists can see through live insects ___ even through solid pieces of metal.",
        "answers": [
            "however",
            "nevertheless",
            "or",
            "yet"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "or"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Anthropologist Guy Swenson ________ that  witchcraft beliefs are prevalent in societies in which social groups interact  without formal mechanisms for social control. ",
        "answers": [
            "he  found",
            "found",
            "finding",
            "was found"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "found"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "True hibernation takes place only among ___animals.",
        "answers": [
            "whose blood is warm",
            "blood warm",
            "warm-blooded",
            "they have warm blood"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "warm-blooded"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The bark of some species of oak trees yields a substance used in ___ leather.",
        "answers": [
            "treating",
            "to treat",
            "its treatment",
            "it treats"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "treating"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ about individuals who really existed and things that actually happened.",
        "answers": [
            "Folktales which sometimes tell stories",
            "The stories of folktales sometimes telling",
            "Stories sometimes told are when folktales",
            "Folktales sometimes tell stories"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Folktales sometimes tell stories"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": " In a hot, sunny climate, man acclimatizes by eating less, drinking more liquids,  wearing lighter clothing, and ________. ",
        "answers": [
            "skin changes  that darken",
            "his skin may darken",
            "experiencing a  darkening of the skin",
            "darkens his skin"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "experiencing a  darkening of the skin"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Amniocentesis can be used not only to  diagnose fetal disorders ________ the sex of the unborn child with 95 percent  accuracy. ",
        "answers": [
            "but determining",
            "but also determining",
            "but to  determine",
            "but also to determine"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "but also to determine"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "East Liverpool, Ohio, ___the pottery capital of the United States.",
        "answers": [
            "and called",
            "is called",
            "calling",
            "to call"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "is called"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The orchestra are meant to ___ time with the conductor.",
        "answers": [
            "hold",
            "keep",
            "take",
            "show"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "show"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The parcel eventually arrived six weeks later, and not ___ time!",
        "answers": [
            "after",
            "before",
            "since",
            "for"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "since"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "As resident of New Mexico, Dennis Chavez ___ to the House of Representatives in 1930 and to the Senate in1938.",
        "answers": [
            "when elected",
            "elected",
            "who was elected",
            "was elected"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "was elected"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "________ of the United States grown during a Republican  administration. ",
        "answers": [
            "Rarely the federal government has",
            "Rarely has the federal  government",
            "Has the federal government  rarely",
            "The federal government has rarely"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Rarely has the federal  government"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ orbits the Sun, Uranus rotates on its axis, an imaginary line through its center.",
        "answers": [
            "For it",
            "It",
            "As it",
            "There is"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "As it"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The light from a laser differs _____ produced by other sources, such as electric bulbs, fluorescent lamps, and the sun.",
        "answers": [
            "from the light",
            "and the light",
            "the light that is",
            "the light can be"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "from the light"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "________ he would have come to class. ",
        "answers": [
            "If Mike is able to finish his  homework",
            "Would Mike be able to finish his homework",
            "If Mike could  finish his homework",
            "If Mike had been able to finish his  homework"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "If Mike had been able to finish his  homework"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": " All the cereal grains ________ grow on the prairies and plains of the United  States. ",
        "answers": [
            "but rice",
            "except the rice",
            "but for rice",
            "excepting  rice"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "but rice"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Generally  speaking, people should have ________ as their desires will allow. ",
        "answers": [
            "much  education",
            "as much education",
            "education",
            "for education"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "as much education"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "According to anthropologists, the earliest ancestors of humans that stood upright resembled chimpanzees ___, with sloping foreheads and protruding brows.",
        "answers": [
            "facially",
            "their faces",
            "having facial",
            "they had faces"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "facially"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": ". Robert S. Duncanson was considered a painter of the Hudson River school, ___on scenes of America\u2019s untamed wilderness",
        "answers": [
            "which concentrated",
            "which concentrated it",
            "which it concentrated",
            "and which concentrated"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "which concentrated"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Before Geraldine Ferraro was selected as the Democratic Party\u2019s vice presidential candidate in 1984, no woman ___ run for national office in the United States on a major party ticket.",
        "answers": [
            "ever has",
            "never had",
            "had ever",
            "having never"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "had ever"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "_____, the silvery-checked hornbill chooses a hollow tree for a nest and seals herself in until her chicks are grown.",
        "answers": [
            "Protection for predators against",
            "Against protection predators for",
            "For protection against predators",
            "Predators against protection for"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "For protection against predators"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "__________ struck, a tuning fork produces an almost pure tone, retaining its pitch over a long period of time.",
        "answers": [
            "When is it",
            "One is",
            "When it is",
            "Is one"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "When it is"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ were stones piled at intervals",
        "answers": [
            "The earliest road markers",
            "The earliest road markers, which",
            "Road markers were the earliest",
            "Until the earliest road markers"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "The earliest road markers"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "According to anthropologists, the earliest ancestors of humans that stood upright resembled chimpanzees ___, with sloping foreheads and protruding brows.",
        "answers": [
            "facially",
            "their faces",
            "having facial",
            "they had faces"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "facially"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Scientists think ___helps some tree to conserve water in the winter.",
        "answers": [
            "when losing leaves",
            "leaves are lost",
            "that losing leaves",
            "the leaves losing"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "that losing leaves"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Using many symbols makes ___ to put a large amount of information on a single map.",
        "answers": [
            "possible",
            "it possible",
            "it is possible",
            "that possible"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "it possible"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "From her early teens ___.",
        "answers": [
            "Blanche Willis Howard\u2019s determination to be an author",
            "Was determined to be an author, Blanche Willis Howard",
            "Blanche Willis Howard was determined to be an author",
            "An author, Blanche Willis Howard was determined to be"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Blanche Willis Howard was determined to be an author"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The skyscraper, ___,is an architectural form that originated in the United States.",
        "answers": [
            "is a tall commercial structure",
            "a tall commercial structure",
            "a tall commercial structure which",
            "of which a tall commercial structure"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "a tall commercial structure"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Ostriches are ___ of living birds, attaining a height from crown to foot of about 2.4 meters and a weight of up to 136 kilograms.",
        "answers": [
            "large, strong",
            "large and strong",
            "larger and strong",
            "the largest and strongest"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "the largest and strongest"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "__________1895 did Cornell University begin to offer a degree in ornithology.",
        "answers": [
            "Not until",
            "Not since",
            "Until",
            "In"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Not until"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "When water freezes in the cracks of rocks, ___ expands, causing the rocks to break apart.",
        "answers": [
            "it",
            "but",
            "then",
            "and"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "it"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The belief in life after death is  prevalent in both primitive societies ________ advanced cultures. ",
        "answers": [
            " and",
            "and in",
            "and also",
            "also"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": " and"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ a continuous mass of water on the Earth\u2019s surface, all continents are islands in the strictest sense of the word.",
        "answers": [
            "The form of the oceans",
            "Since the oceans form",
            "To form the oceans",
            "That the oceans form"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Since the oceans form"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "In the late 1800\u2019s Ellen Richards, began work in the new field of \u201csanitary science\u201d which was concerned with waste removal, water purification and ___.",
        "answers": [
            "to ventilate adequately",
            "adequate ventilation",
            "adequate ventilate",
            "ventilation adequately"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "adequate ventilation"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "His invention showed that he understood what was going to happen in the future and proved he was ___ of his time.",
        "answers": [
            "in front",
            "before",
            "ahead",
            "forward"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "ahead"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The oldest city in the state, ___",
        "answers": [
            "the Hudson\u2019s Bay Company founded Vancouver, Washington, in the early nineteenth century",
            "the founding of Vancouver, Washington, by the Hudson\u2019s Bay Company in the early nineteenth century",
            "Vancouver, Washington, was founded by the Hudson\u2019s Bay Company in the early nineteenth century",
            "In the early nineteenth century with the founding of Vancouver, Washington, by the Hudson\u2019s Bay Company"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "In the early nineteenth century with the founding of Vancouver, Washington, by the Hudson\u2019s Bay Company"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "___ became a state in 1876",
        "answers": [
            "When Colorado",
            "Colorado",
            "It was Colorado",
            "Colorado, which"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "Colorado"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Uniform acceleration occurs __________the rate of change remains the same over successive and equal intervals of time.",
        "answers": [
            "according",
            "if",
            "with",
            "under"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "if"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "Experiments in the photography of moving objects __________ in both the United States and Europe well before 1900.",
        "answers": [
            "have been conducting",
            "were conducting",
            "had been conducted",
            "being conducted"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "had been conducted"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "The slide rule uses sliding scales with marks ___ numbers and their logarithms.",
        "answers": [
            "representing",
            "represented",
            "are represented",
            "they are representing"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "representing"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "American author John Updike,  ________ spent his boyhood in Shillington, Pennsylvania. ",
        "answers": [
            "was the only  child of a high school mathematics teacher",
            "whom the only child of a  high school mathematics teacher",
            "the only child of a high school  mathematics teacher",
            "he was the only child of a high school  mathematics teacher"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "the only child of a high school  mathematics teacher"
    },
    {
        "content": "",
        "question": "________, Cart Sandburg is also well known for his  multivolume biography of Lincoln. ",
        "answers": [
            "An eminent American poet",
            "He is an eminent American  poet",
            "An eminent American poet who is",
            "Despite an eminent American  poet"
        ],
        "rightAnswer": "An eminent American poet"
    }
]